<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on vranix</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on vranix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:47:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Geniveev: a CLI for boilerplate generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/geniveev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:47:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/geniveev/</guid>
      <description>I worked on a product with a microservice architecture for a while. As one does working in such an environment, I found myself creating a lot of little services. Each of these services was first described as a service in a protobuf file. The services were compiled into an interface which you would then implement. We also used a tool for injecting dependencies to make creating these services easier.&#xA;This is a long way for me to say that to start a new project, I would generally have to create three files in different (new) directories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>home-manager neovim setup: embedded lua highlighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/lua-highlighting-homemanager-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 06:47:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/lua-highlighting-homemanager-vim/</guid>
      <description>Problem I use home-manager to manage my neovim configuration. When using a plugin, a typical configuration snippet might look like this:&#xA;{ plugin = neogit; type = &amp;#34;lua&amp;#34;; config = &amp;#39;&amp;#39; require(&amp;#39;neogit&amp;#39;).setup { disable_commit_confirmation = true, integrations = { diffview = true, } } &amp;#39;&amp;#39;; } This works well enough for me. I like how I can specify the configuration for a plugin next to where I specify the plugin itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive Dev Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/productive-dev-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 14:01:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/productive-dev-setup/</guid>
      <description>Creating a productive dev environment The nicest thing about frontend end development is the speed by which you can write code and see the changes in the browser. Most frameworks ship with this experience out of the box and if you&amp;rsquo;re using it for your backend too, the development experience is really phenomenal. As soon as you start adding services however, this development experience breaks down.&#xA;Say you&amp;rsquo;ve got a nextjs app hitting a golang backend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective One: Innovative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/retrospective-one-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 19:20:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/retrospective-one-iii/</guid>
      <description>Many moons ago, at the dot-com bubble burst I got my first programming job in the San Francisco Bay Area at a software company that made software for libraries. I had recently returned from a year in Germany where I had concentrated on learning to read German and hadn&amp;rsquo;t touched a computer in that time, other than writing emails and papers. I had come into college extremely excited about programming and had to learn the hard way that computer science is not programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems with self-hosting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/fixing-selfhosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:10:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/fixing-selfhosting/</guid>
      <description>Even nerds don&amp;rsquo;t want to run their own servers This is a quote from Moxie Marlinspike&amp;rsquo;s post My first impressions of web3. This article is great critique of web3. He makes a number of good points, but what I found most interesting was his assertion that people do not want to run their own servers. And I cannot stop thinking about this and not b/c I think he&amp;rsquo;s wrong, but b/c I think these challenges can be overcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nix dev shells from 10,000 feet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/nix-devshells/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 12:37:53 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/nix-devshells/</guid>
      <description>Setting the scene After neglecting this small place on the internet for years, I cloned the repo with the hope of quickly updating my resume. This site is constructed with Hugo, which is a static site generator written in golang. Anyway, I needed to install that too, so I edited my home-manager configuration and switched, i.e., I installed it.&#xA;There was an attempt First thing I tried was running &amp;ldquo;hugo serve&amp;rdquo; which starts a web server and serves the content of your hugo project so changes can be seen as you make them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
